He will challenge their traditions. Their traditions will change his life.
Stomp the Yard is a drama, music film directed by Sylvain White.
After the death of his younger brother, a troubled 19-year-old street dancer from Los Angeles is able to
bypass juvenile hall by enrolling in the historically black, Truth University in Atlanta, Georgia.
But his efforts to get an education and woo the girl he likes are sidelined when he is courted by the top two campus fraternities, both
of which want and need his fierce street-style dance moves to win the highly coveted national step show competition.
DJ, played by Columbus Short.
April, played by Meagan Good.
Rich Brown, played by Ne-Yo.
Grant, played by Darrin Henson.
Noel, played by Jermaine Williams.
Duron, played by Chris Brown.
Stomp the Yard is a 2007 American dance drama film  produced by Rainforest Films and
released through Sony Pictures' Screen Gems division on January 12, 2007.
Directed by Sylvain White, Stomp the Yard centers on DJ Williams, a college student at a fictional
historically black university who pledges to join a fictional Greek-letter fraternity.
The film's central conflict involves DJ's fraternity competing in various
stepping competitions against a rival fraternity of the same school.
The film's script was written by Robert Adetuyi, working from
an original draft by Gregory Ramon Anderson.
The film was originally titled Steppin', but to avoid confusion
over the 2006 film Step Up, the title was changed.
Delta Sigma Theta along with other sororities
like Gamma Theta were in the movie.
The film stars Columbus Short, Meagan Good, Darrin Henson, Brian White, Laz Alonso, and Valarie
Pettiford, with Harry Lennix, and, in their film debuts, R&B singers Ne-Yo & Chris Brown.
Stomp the Yard was filmed in Atlanta, Georgia, on the campuses of Morris Brown College, Georgia Institute of Technology,
Morehouse College, and Clark Atlanta University, and in the MAK Historic District of Decatur, Georgia.
Elsewhere Short, Alonso and Brown had also starred
together in the film This Christmas.
The film explores themes of daughter, loss of loved
one, love at first sight, breakdance.
The tone is emotional.